MD. AZAM IRSHAD

AUTOMATION ENGINEER



+9

+91-7761816304

 \bigvee

iazam44@hotmail.com

9

Ramzan Colony, Kantatoli, Ranchi

PROFILE

Results- driven engineer with a graduate degree and 4 years of experience. I have hands on experience with Siemens PLC, HMI, AutoCAD and SCADA. I have also worked on several VFD ranging from different rating to different manufacturer.

SKILLS

- Siemens TIA Portal
- Siemens Step 7
- Win CC
- PLC Programming
- VFD Parameterization
- HMI and SCADA Programming
- Control Panel Design
- AutoCAD

EDUCATION

POLYTECHNIC DIPLOMA

RTC Institute of Technology 2015 - 2018

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

RTC Institute of Technology 2018 - 2021

EXPERIENCE

AUTOMATION ENGINEER

Advanced Electrical and Automation Solutions

August 2018 - Present

- Prepare technical drawings, specifications of electrical systems, or topographical maps to ensure that installation and operations conform to standards and customer requirements.
- Design, implement, maintain, or improve electrical instruments, equipment, facilities, components, products, or systems for commercial, industrial, or domestic purposes.
- Prepare specifications for purchases of materials or equipment.
- Selection of PLC and/or VFD according to the client's requirement and write appropriate ladder logic programming.
- Providing with the guidance and installation of VFD.
- Design and construct the control panel.
- Wiring and testing of control panel.

ELECTRICAL MAINTENANCE ENGINEER

Naresh Kumar Company & Pvt Ltd

August 2022 - October 2022

- Overseeing every panel and maintaining optimal performance.
- Troubleshooting kilowatt range motors.
- Assisting Tata Steel Engineer in installation of 11KV transformer.

PRIMARY SKILLS

- PLC Programming
- VFD Parameterization
- AutoCAD Design
- HMI and SCADA Programming
- C Language
- C++ Language
- Computer Network

OTHER KNOWN SKILLS

- Web Development
- MySQL
- PHP
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Arduino Programming

OTHER INFORMATION

- I am fluent in Hindi, English and Urdu.
- My hobbies include watch YouTube videos, learn about international history, play video games.

PROJECTS

- Conveyor belt with oversize object detection and alarm system.
- Auto/Manual start selection of DG generator.
- Installation of 132 kW VFD (L&T Fx2000 series)
- Various D.O.L starter for various motor rating.
- Designed and constructed 4 pairs of training kit including Siemens S7-1200 series PLC and VFD from Siemens, Yaskawa.
- Design, construction and installation of Control panel for Electrification of 5 floor residential flat.
- Assisting in installation of 11KV Transformer.
- Troubleshooting kilowatt range motors

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

• Father's Name: Irshad Ahmad

• Mother's Name: Nazneen Bano

• Date of Birth: 15-01-1997

Address: Shakil Ansari's House, Road
No. 2, Ramzan Colony, Kanta Toli,
Ranchi, Jharkhand - 834001.

DECLARATION